Guide to the Lincoln Collection, American Historical Portraits 19th-20th centuries
University of Chicago Library
Lincoln Collection. American Historical Portraits
19th-20th centuries
24.5 linear feet (8 boxes, 3 oversized folders)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The American Historical Portraits collection forms part of the William E. Barton Collection of Lincolniana. The majority of the materials in this collection are portraits of political figures; statesmen and soldiers. Included among these are a small number of affiliated professionals, such as writers, clergymen, naturalists, and artists.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) The Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) was one of the early twentieth century's most prominent writers and lecturers on the life of Abraham Lincoln. Born in Sublette, Illinois, in the same year Lincoln assumed the presidency, Barton grew up in an environment heavily influenced by reverence for Lincoln. After pursuing undergraduate studies at Berea College in Kentucky, Barton earned his divinity degree from the Oberlin Theological Seminary in 1890. He served parishes in Tennessee, Ohio, and Massachusetts before becoming the pastor of the First Congregational Church of Oak Park, Illinois, a position he held until his retirement in 1924. Four years later, Barton accepted an appointment as lecturer at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, where he also organized and served as pastor of the Collegeside Congregational Church.
Barton's work as a writer produced a number of denominational manuals for church organization and a series of books presenting the wisdom and parables of a character he named Safed the Sage. For the last ten years of his life, however, Barton was best known to the public as a prolific author and lecturer on Abraham Lincoln. His publications about Lincoln included The Soul of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Paternity of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Life of Abraham Lincoln (1925), The Great and Good Man (1927), The Women Lincoln Loved (1927), and The Lincoln of the Biographers (1930).
In the course of compiling material for his writings and talks, Barton visited Lincoln sites in Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois; interviewed surviving Lincoln relatives and acquaintances; and traveled as far as California and England to collect information and conduct genealogical research on the ancestry of the Lincoln family. While acquiring a large collection of books, periodicals, pamphlets, manuscripts, and ephemera related to Lincoln and the Civil War era, Barton also purchased privately or at auction historical materials amassed by other Lincoln collectors such as John E. Burton and Osborn H. Oldroyd.
Scope Note
This collection is made up of materials compiled by William E. Barton. A pastor in Oak Park, Illinois, Barton published and lectured on Lincoln extensively. He also maintained connections with fellow Lincoln experts and carried out multiple research projects that delved into the many different facets of Lincoln’s life, times and family history.
The majority of the materials in this collection are portraits of political figures; statesmen and soldiers. Included among these are a small number of non state affiliated professionals, such as writers, clergymen, naturalists, and artists. This collection has been organized in consideration of the material’s size and aimed to make portraits of individuals readily accessible to researchers.
This collection is organized into three series: Series I: Individual Portraits, Series II: Group Portraits and Series III: Oversized Portraits.
Series I is arranged alphabetically and contains individual portraits of presidents, statesmen, abolitionists, clergymen, artists and writers. Series II is an arrangement of group portraits; engravings and photographs, whose subject matters centers on the Civil War. These include group images of the Union and Confederate armies represented under central themes, such as Naval Officers or a General with his Officers of Staff.
Series III contains oversized materials and is organized into two subseries; mirroring the two prior series. Subseries 1 are oversized individual portraits, arranged alphabetically. There are also presidential portraits accompanied with a biography of the individual housed here. Subseries 2 contains oversized group portraits of Presidents, United States Independence Anniversary, and Carrier’s of the Press. Please note there are also three photographs picturing William E. Barton housed here.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Barton, William Eleazar, 1861-1930; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865; Collectors and collecting -- United States
INVENTORY
- Series I: Individual Portraits
  This series is composed of engravings, lithographs, and drawings of historical American figures. They are arranged alphabetically for accessibility.
  - Portraits, Abercrombie to Adams, Abercrombie, John J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Adams, John, President Adams, John Quincy, President (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portraits, Alger to Ayers, Alger, Russel A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Allston, Washington, Artist Ames, Adelbert, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ammen, Daniel, Rear Admiral U.S.A. Ammen, Jacob, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Anderson, Robert, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Anderson, Robert H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Andrew, John A., Gov. of Mass. Andrews, George L., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Archer, James J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Armstrong, Samuel C., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Arnold, Isaac N., Congressman, Lincoln biographer Asboth, Alexander, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Astor, John Jacob, Capitalist Astor, John Jacob Jr., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Astor, John Jacob, Capitalist Audubon, John J., Artist, naturalist Augur, C.C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Averell, W.W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ayres, Romeyn Beck, Rear Admiral U.S.A. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Portraits, Bacon to Berry, Bacon, Henry, Architect Bailey, Theodorus, Rear Admiral U.S.A. Baird, William Henderson, Lt. Col. N.Y. Vols. Baker, Edward D., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Baker, Lawrence S., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Bancroft, George, Historian Banks, Nathaniel P., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Barlow, Francis C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Barnes, James, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Barnes, John G., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Barney, Joshua, Naval officer Barney, Lewis T., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Barnum, Henry A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Barry, John, Naval officer Barry, William. F., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Barton, Seth M., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Bates, Edward, Attorney Gen. U.S.A. Baxter, DeWitt Clinton, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Baxter, Henry, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Beadle, William. H.H., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Beatty, John, Gen. C.S.A. Beauregard, G.P.T., Gen. C.S.A. Bee, Barnard, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Beecher, Henry Ward, Clergyman, Abolitionist Belknap, William W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Bell, Henry H., Rear Admiral U.S.A. Bendix, John E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Benedict, Lewis, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Benham, Henry W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Benton, Thomas H., Statesman Berdan, Hiram, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Berry, Hiram G., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Portraits, Biddle to Brown, Biddle, Charles. J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Bingham, John A., Congressman, Ohio Bingham, Judson D., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Birney, David B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Black, Hawk, Indian Chief Blaine, James G., Statesman, Pres. Candidate Blair, Frank P., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Blair, Montgomery, Postmaster Gen. U.S.A. Blenker, Louis, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Boggs, Charles S., Capt. U.S.A. Bohlen, Henry, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Bonham, Milledge L. Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Boone, Daniel, Frontiersman Booth, Edwin, Actor Booth, John Wilkes, Lincoln's assassin Boutwell, George S., Politician Boyd, Belle, Rebel spy Boynton, Henry Van Ness, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Bradley, Luther P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Bragg, Braxton, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Brannon, John M., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Breck, Samuel, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Breckenridge, John C., Maj. Gen. C.S.A.; V. Pres, U.S.A. Breeze, Commodore, U.S.N. Briggs, Henry S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Brooke, John R., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Brooks, William. T.H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Brown, Aaron V., A Brown, Egbert B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Brown, Jacob, Soldier (1812) Brown, John, Abolitionist, A (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Portraits, Bryant to Butterfield, Bryant, William Cullen, Poet Buchanan, Franklin, Commodore U.S.N. Buchanan, James, President Buckingham, C.P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Buckingham, William A., Gov. of Conn. Buckland, Ralph P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Buckner, Simon B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Buell, Don Carlos, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Buford, John, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Burbridge, Stephen A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Burger, Louis, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Burns, Michael W., Col. N.Y. Vols. Burns, Robert, Scottish Poet Burnside, Ambrose E., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Burr, Aaron, Politician Busted, Richard, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Butler, Benjamin F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Butterfield, Daniel, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Portraits, Caldwell to Clinton, Caldwell, John C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Calhoun, J.C., Statesman, V.P. Senator Camerson, Simon, Senator (Penn.), Sec. of War Campbell, J.A., Postmaster General (?) Candy, Edward R.S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Carlin, William. P., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Carr, Eugene A., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Carr, Joseph B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Carrington, Henry B., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Carson, Kit, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Casey, Silas, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Cass, Lewis, Senator (Mich.), Pres. Candidate Chamberlain, Joshua L., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Champlin, Stephen G., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Chandler, Zachariah, Senator (Mich.) Chase, Salmon Portland, Sec. of Treasury Cheatham, Benjamin F., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Chetlain, Augustus E., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Chickering, Thomas E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Choate, Rufus, Senator (Mass.) Cilly, Jonathan P., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Clay, Cassius M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Clay, Henry, Senator (Ky.), A Clayton, Powell, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cleveland, Grover, President Clingman, Thomas L., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Clinton, DeWitt, Gov. of N.Y., Presidential candidate Clinton, George, Soldier (Revolution) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Portraits, Cobb to Cox, Cobb, George T., A Cobb, Howell, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Coburn, John, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cochran, John, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cody, W.F. (Buffalo Bill), Scout, showman Coffin, Charles Carleton, Writer Cole, George W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Colfax, Schuyler, Congressman, Vice-Pres. Collis, Charles. H.T., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Colquitt, Alfred Holt, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Colston, Raleigh E., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Conkling, Roscoe, Senator (N.Y.), A Conner, James, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Cook, Burton C., Congressman (Ill.) Cook, John, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cooke, John R., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Cooke, Phillip St. G., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cooper, James, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cooper, James Fenimore, Author Cooper, Joseph A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cooper, Samuel, Gen. C.S.A. Copeland, Joseph T., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Corcoran, Michael, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Couch, Darius N., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Cowdin, Robert, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cox, J.D., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Cox, Samuel S., Congressman (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Portraits, Crane to Custer, Crane, Charles H., Surgeon Gen., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Crawford, Samuel W., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Crittenden, John J., Senator (Ky.) Crocker, Marcellus M., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Crossman, George H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Cullum, George W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Cullum, Shelby M., Representative (Ill.) Curtin, A.G., Gov. of Penn. Curtis, Benjamin Robbins, Jurist Curtis, N. Martin, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Curtis, Samuel R., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Cushing, William H., Commander U.S.N. Custer, George A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Portraits, Jefferson Davis, Davis, Jefferson, President, C.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Portraits, Dahlgren to Dow, Dahlgren, John A., Admiral U.S.N. Dana, Napoleon J.T., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Davidson, John W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Davies, Henry E., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Davies, Thomas A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Davis, Charles Henry, U.S.N. Davis, David, Jurist Davis, Jefferson C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Day, Hannibal, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dayton, Jonathan, Soldier, Congressman Dayton, O.D., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dayton, William L., Senator, Ambassador Decatur, Stephen, Naval officer (1812) Deitzler, George W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dennis, Elias S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dennison, William., Gov. of Ohio Dent, Frederick T., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Denver, James W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. De Trobriand, Philip Regis, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Devens, Charles J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Devin, Thomas C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dewitt, David P., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dimick, Justin, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dix, John A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Dodge, Charles C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Dodge, Grenville M., Maj. Gen. U.S.A., Senator (Iowa) Donaldson, James. L., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Doolittle, Charles A., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Doubleday, Abner, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Dow, Neal, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Portraits, Stephen A. Douglas, Douglas, Stephen A., Senator (Ill.) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Portraits, Drake to Duryee:, Drake, Charles D., Senator (Mo.) Drayton, Thomas F., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. DuPont, S.F., Commodore, U.S.N. Duryee, Abram, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Portraits, Early to Faunce, Early, Jubal A., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Eaton, Amos B., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Echols, John, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Edwards, Clark S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Edwards, Oliver, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Elliott, Stephen J., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Elliott, W.L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Ellsworth, Elmer E., Col. U.S.A. Ellswoth, Oliver, Chief Justice Elzey, Arnold, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Ericsson, John, Rear Admiral U.S.N., inventor of "Monitor" Everett, Edward, Scholar, statesman Ewell, Richard, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Ewing, Thomas, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Farnsworth, Addison, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Farnsworth, Elon J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Farnsworth, John F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Farnum, J. Egbert, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Farragut, David G., Admiral U.S.N. Faunce, John, Admiral U.S.N. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Portraits, Featherstone to Fulton, Featherstone, W.S., Gen. C.S.A. Fell, Jesse W., Minister Ferrero, Edward, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Ferry, Odwis S., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Fessenden, Francis, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Fessenden, William P., Senator (Maine) Fillmore, Millard, President Fisk, Frank E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Fitzpatrick, Stephen, Actor Florence, Thomas B., Congressman (Penn.) Flovd, John B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Foote, Andrew Hull, Rear Admiral U.S.N. Force, Manning F., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Forrest, Nathan B., Gen. C.S.A. Foster, John G., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Foster, Robert S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Fowert, ?, Commodore, C.S.N. Fox, Gustavus Vasa, Assistant Sec. of Navy Franklin, Benjamin, Statesman, printer Franklin, William Buell, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Frazer, Douglas, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Frehlinghuysen, Frederick T., Senator (N.Y.) Fremont, Jesse Benton, Wife of John C. Fremont, John C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A., Presidential candidate (also Currier & Ives) Frost, Daniel M., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Fry, James. B., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Fry, Speed S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Fuller, John W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Fulton, Robert, Artist, inventor, engineer (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Portraits, Gage to Grover, Gage, Joseph S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Gallatin, Albert, Sec. of Treasury Gamble, William., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Gardner, William. M., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Garfield, James A., President Garland, Samuel, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Garrard, Kenner, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Garrard, Theophilus, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Gates, Horatio, Soldier (Revolution) Geary, John W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Gibbon, John, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Gibbs, Alfred, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Gillem, Alvan C., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Gillmore, Quincy A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Gilmer, David A., Col. U.S.A. Gilmer, John A., Congressman Girard, Stephen, Financier Glasgow, S.S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Goldsborough, Louis M., Rear Admiral U.S.N. Goodwin, Ichabod, Gov. of N.H. Gordon, John B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Gordon, George W., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Gorman, Willis A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Graham, Charles K., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Granger, Gordon, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Granger, Robert S., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Grant, Ulysses S., Lieut. Gen. U.S.A., President Greeley, Horace, Editor, political leader Green, Martin E., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Greene, Nathaniel E., General (Revolution) Gregg, David McM., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Gregg, John, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Gregg, Maxey, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Gregory, Francis H., Com. U.S.N. Grierson, Benjamin H., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Griffin, Charles, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Griffin, Simon G., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Grose, William., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Grover, Cuvier, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Portraits, Hackleman to Hazen, Hackleman, P.A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Halleck, Henry W., General-in-Chief U.S.A. Hamblin, Joseph E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hamilton, Alexander, Statesman Hamilton, Andrew J., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hamilton, Charles S., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hamilton, Schuyler, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hamlin, Hannibal, Vice-President, U.S.A. Hampton, Wade Gen. C.S.A. Hancock, John, Statesman Hancock, Winfield S., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (See: also in oversize) Hanson, Roger W., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Hardesty, William, Washington Co., Ky. Settler Hardin, M.D., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Harker, Charles G., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Harlan, Edward, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Harlan, Emory B., General, U.S.A. Harlan, James., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Senator (Iowa) Harney, W.S., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Harrison, Benjamin, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A., Pres. Harrison, William H., President Hartranft, John F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hartsaff, George L., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Haskin, Joseph A., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hatch, Edward, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hawkins, Rush C., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hawley, Joseph R., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hayes, Rutherford B., President Hayne, Robert Y., Senator, Gov. of S. Carolina Hays, Harry T., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hazen, William B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Portraits, Head to Hurlbut, Head, Jesse, Clergyman to Lincoln's parents Heckman, Charles Adam, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Heintzelman, Samuel P., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Henry, Patrick, Statesman Herold, David C., Lincoln assassin Herron, Francis J., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Heth, Henry, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hickenlooper, Andrew, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hill, Ambrose, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hill, Daniel H., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hindman, Thomas C., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hinks, Edward W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hitcock, Ethan Allen, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hobson, E.H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hoke, Robert F., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hollins, George N., C.S.N. Holman, W.S., Congressman (Ind.) Holt, Joseph, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hood, John B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Hooker, Joseph, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hopkinson, Francis, Statesman Hovey, Alvin P., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Howard, O.O., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hull, J.B., Comm. U.S.N. Humphreys, Andres A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Hunt, Lewis C., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hunter, David, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hunter, R.M.T., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Hunton, Eppa, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Hurlbut, Stephen A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Portraits, Ingalls to Julian, Ingalls, Rufus, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Ingraham, Timothy, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Irving, Washington, Writer, Diplomat Isherwood, Benjamin F., Rear Admiral U.S.A. Jackson, Andrew, President Jackson, Joseph C., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Jackson, Thomas J. (Stonewall), Lieut. Gen. C.S.A. Jay, John, Statesman Jefferson, Thomas, President Jenkins, Albert G., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Johnson, Andrew, President U.S.A. Johnson, Reverdy, Lawyer, diplomat Johnson, Richard W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Johnston, Joseph. E., Ger. C.S.A. Jones, John Paul, Naval officer (Revolution) Jones, Patrick H., Gen. U.S.A. Jones, Samuel, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Judd, Norman B., Congressman (Ill.) Julian, George W., Congressman (Ind.) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Portraits, Kane to Knox, Kane, Elisha K., Arctic explorer Kane, Thomas L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Kautz, August V., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Kearney, Philip, Maj. Ggn. U.S.A. Keifer, J. Warren, Brvt. aj. Gen. U.S.A. Keim, Wm. H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Kelley, B.F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Kelley, William D., Congressman (Penn.) Kelton, John C., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Kenly, John R., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Kent, James, Jurist Kershaw, Jos. B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Ketcham, John H., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Keyes, Erasmus D., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Kilpatrick, Judson, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Kimball, Nathan, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. King, Rufus, Statesman King, Rufus (grandson of above), Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Knox, Henry, Maj. Gen., Sec. of War (Rev.) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Portraits, Lafayette to Lawrence, Lafayette, Marquis de, Soldier (Revolution) Lander, Frederick W., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Lane, James H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Lane, Walter P., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Lansing, Henry S., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Lansing, John, Jurist Lauman, Jacob, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Laurens, Henry, Merchant, statesman, A Lawrence, Abbott, Statesman, diplomat, etc. Lawrence, James, Naval officer (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Portraits, Lee to Leggett, Lee, Albert L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Lee, Fitzhugh, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Lee, Henry, Soldier (Revolution) Lee, Richard Henry, Statesman Lee, Robert E., General C.S.A. Lee, William H.F., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Lee, William Raymond, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Leggett, Mortimer D., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Portraits, Lincoln to Lyon, Lincoln, Benjamin, Soldier (Revolution) Lippincott, C.E., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Livingston, Robert R., Jurist Lockwood, Henry H., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Logan, John A., Maj, Gen, Photograph of residence, Washington DC Longfellow, Henry W., Poet Longstreet, James, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Loomis, Cyrus O., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Lovell, Mansfield, Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Lyon, Hylan B., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Lyon, Nathaniel, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Portraits, McAllister to McCullough, McAllister, Robert, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McArthur, John Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McCall, George A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McCallum, David S., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McCandless, William, Brig. Gen. U.S.A., & McClellan, George B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McClernand, John A., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McClure, T.J., 1st Lieut. U.S.A. McCook, Alexander McD., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McCook, Robert L. Brig. Gen U.S.A. McCulloch, Hugh, Sec. of Treasury McCullough, Ben., Brig. Gen. C.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Portraits, McDougal to Maury, McDougal, Thomas, Naval officer McDowell, Irvin, Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McGowan, Samuel, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. McGrorty, Stephen J., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McHenry, James, Secretary of War McIntosh, John B., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McKeever, Chauncy, Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McKinley, William, President McKinstry, Justus, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McLean, John McLean, Nathaniel C., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. McLane, John McMahon, Martin T., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McMillan, James W., Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McNeill, John, Brvt. Maj. Gen. U.S.A. McPherson, Jas. B., Maj. Gen. U.S.A. Madison, James, President Maguire, C., Captain, U.S.A. Magruder, John B., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Mahone, Wm., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. Maltby, Jasper A., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Manderson, Charles. F., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Mansfield, Joseph K.F., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Marcy, Randolph B., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Marion, Francis, General (Revolution) Marshall, Humphrey, Brig. Gen. C.S.A. Marshall, John, Chief Justice Supreme Court Marshall, William R., Brvt. Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Marston, Gelman, Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Mason, George, Statesman Matthies, Charles L., Brig. Gen. U.S.A. Maury, Dabney H., Maj. Gen. C.S.A. (Box 4, Folder 24)